Czechoslovakia Subject Files, Inclusive: 1946-2004, undated, Bulk: 1977-1989
Baylor University, The Keston Center for Religion, Politics, and Society
Czechoslovakia Subject Files
Inclusive: 1946-2004, undated, Bulk: 1977-1989
Baylor University, The Keston Center for Religion, Politics, and Society http://www.baylor.edu/kestoncenter/
1
Keston Institute, 1969 -
39 A4 document boxes.
The Czechoslovakia Subject Files contain a variety of materials on religion and atheism, persecution of clergy and believers, human rights activity, and major historical events in Czechoslovakia.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Average.
Biography/Profile
Keston College, originally founded in 1969 as the Center for the Study of Religion and Communism with the named changed to Keston College in 1974, collected and publicized details about religious persecution behind the Iron Curtain, becoming “the voice of the voiceless.” After the collapse of communism in the 1990s, Keston College moved to Oxford and downsized due to decreased funding. The name eventually changed to Keston Institute. In 2007, the Institute transferred the Keston Archive and Library to the newly created Keston Center for Religion, Politics, and Society at Baylor University.
Keston collected, verified, translated, and disseminated information received from believers in the Soviet Union, Poland, Romania, Czechoslovakia, Hungary, Yugoslavia, Bulgaria and other communist countries. The Keston Archive and Library housed numerous letters, petitions, reports and underground publications (Samizdat) from believers of various denominations along with officially published books and periodicals.
From the beginning of the post-World War II period until approximately 2004, Keston obtained materials documenting the religious and political climate and persecution in Czechoslovakia, a country that obtained independence from the Austro-Hungarian Empire and existed from 1918-1992. From 1938-1945, Nazi Germany occupied Czechoslovakia and the Soviet Union controlled the country from 1948-1989. On January 1, 1993, Czechoslovakia peacefully separated into the Czech Republic and Slovakia.
In 1918, Czechoslovakia brought together the historic lands of Bohemia, Moravia and Slovakia with Tomas Masaryk elected the first president. However, the leaders of Great Britain, France, Italy and GermanyDLNeville Chamberlain, Edouard Daladier, Benito Mussolini, and Adolf HitlerDLsigned the Munich Agreement in September 1938. The document passed control of the border areas of Czechoslovakia known as Sudetenland to Hitler’s Germany. Because the Czechs had aligned themselves militarily with France and Britain, the event is sometimes referred to as “About us, without us!” and led to significant oppression.
Although many believed the country would recover its freedom following WW II, the “Victorious February” or “Czech Coup” dashed those hopes for more than 40 years. On February, 28, 1948, the Communist Party of Czechoslovakia took total control, leading to religious, political, economic and cultural repression and the need for Keston’s efforts in collecting, documenting, and disseminating information about the situation.
The 1950’s may have been the most depressive decade in the post-war period. Collectivization, nationalization, elimination of private business, political repression and religious persecution led to general fear. Opponents of the regime were forced to emigrate, intimidated, or silenced like political leader Dr. Milada Horáková who was executed and priest Josef Toufar who was tortured to his death. Many died or languished in prison.
With Nikita Khrushchev’s assent to power in the USSR during the 1960’s, change occurred in Czechoslovakia as well, bringing modern ideas, societal transformation and political liberalization. The brief liberalization period that began on January 5 and ended on August 21, 1968, became known as Prague Spring. Alexander Dubček, First Secretary of the Communist Party of Czechoslovakia, introduced “socialism with a human face” that promised to improve overall living conditions. However, on August 21, 1968, Warsaw Pact countries led by the Soviet Union invaded the country “to save the socialism” be stopping reform, consolidating Communist power, and increasing oppression.
The Soviets remained in power for 21 years with Czechoslovakia becoming one of the most progressive and repressive countries in Europe during the 1970’s and 1980’s. Normalization, sometimes named Husákism after President Gustáv Husák, occurred during the 1970’s and included steps and actions following the violent suppression of the Prague Spring. These actions included purges of the Communist Party, restoration of censorship, and elimination of associations and organizations. The first increased expression of resistance against the regime took place with an informal civic initiative called Charter 77. Members such as Václav Havel and Pavel Kohout drafted a human rights document, but the regime considered spreading the text of the document a political crime resulting in persecution.
In 1989, as democratization spread under Soviet leader Mikhail Gorbachev, mass demonstrations occurred in Prague from November 17 through late December, 1989, and led to the Velvet Revolution which ended Communist rule, returned democracy, and allowed the re-emergence of religious freedom. Former dissident Václav Havel became the country’s president, and in free elections held in June 1990, non-communist candidates won by large majorities.
Scope and Content
Czechoslovakia subject files consist of newspaper clippings, bibliographic references, handwritten notes, correspondence, research papers, manuscripts, church and secular publications, reports on issues of religion and atheism, and religious dissidents in Czechoslovakia, and Czech and Slovak Samizdat (underground publications).
The materials cover a period from 1946 to 2004 with the bulk from 1977 to 1989. The most notable topics include, but are not limited to, Charter 77, Prague Spring (1968), and the Velvet Revolution (1989). Some materials pertain to a period following the peaceful separation of Czechoslovakia into the Czech Republic and Slovakia in 1993.
Arrangement
Keston Center received most of the Czechoslovakia materials already arranged in specific categories and denominations. This original filing system has been preserved. The Czechoslovakia materials received by Keston Center in no particular order are arranged thematically and chronologically.
Currently, the Czechoslovakia Subject Files are arranged in two series: I. General and II. Denominational Materials.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to the Keston Center for Religion, Politics, and Society in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 1.
Index Terms
Subjects (Organizations)
Keston College -- Archives.; Keston Institute -- Archives.
Places
Czechoslovakia -- Church history.; Czechoslovakia -- History -- 1968-1989.; Czechoslovakia -- History -- Intervention, 1968.; Czechoslovakia -- History -- Velvet Revolution, 1989.
Subjects
Atheism -- Czechoslovakia.; Christianity -- Czechoslovakia.; Christianity and atheism.; Christians -- Czechoslovakia.; Freedom of religion -- Czechoslovakia.; Human rights movements -- Czechoslovakia.; Persecution -- Czechoslovakia.; Political persecution -- Czechoslovakia.; Propaganda, Communist -- Czechoslovakia.; Religious education -- Czechoslovakia.; Underground literature -- Czechoslovakia.
Genres
Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.); Correspondence.; Samizdat.
- General, 1946-2001, undated; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Average.
  Biography/Profile
  General Czechoslovakia subject files contain materials on religious persecution, human rights activity, state religious policies, atheist propaganda, communist ideology, and political dissidents, including Carter 77, 1968 Soviet invasion, and peaceful separation of Czechoslovakia into the Czech Republic and Slovakia in 1993.
  - History, 1950, 1973-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - History (WW II Period), 1983-1988 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - History (Collapse of Communism), 1980-1990 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - History (Communist Period), 1969-1989 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Individuals: Hathaway, David, 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Individuals: Komensky, Jan Amos, 1970-1988 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Individuals: Masaryk, Jan, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - State Government, Nationhood, 1973-1984 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Census-Citizenship-Population, 1982-1988 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - National Identity, 1980-1987 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - National Minorities, 1963-2001 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Nationality Policies, 1976-1989 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Government, 1976-1990 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Elections, 1976-1988 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Individuals, 1977-1989 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Policies, 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - State Administration, 1978-1988 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Military Affairs-Defense, 1978-2001 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Espionage, 1969-1986 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Emigration, 1976-1988 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Statistics, 1968-1982 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Law-Constitution, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Constitution, 1978-1989 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Church and State, 1977-1990 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Basic Rights-Freedom, 1977-1996 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Law, 1964-1989 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Crime, 1977-1989 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - State Police-State Security Organization, 1977-1985 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Prisons-Labor Camp, 1968-1988 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Prisons and Religion, 1977-1987 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Censorship, 1968-1982 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Oppressive Practices, 1978-1989 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Political Trials (1 of 2), 1972 -1982 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Political Trials (2 of 2), 1973 -1988 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Political Imprisonment (1 of 2), 1972-1983 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Political Imprisonment (2 of 2), 1984-1987 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Expulsion of Own Nations, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Misuse of Psychiatry, 1977-1988 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - International Relations (Austria, Federal Republic of Germany, France, Great Britain, United States), 1962-2002 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - International Relations (USSR), 1968-1987 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Foreign Policy, 1976-1989 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Foreign-Visas-Smuggling-Personal Contacts, 1963-1989 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Expulsion of Foreigners From the Country, 1978-1988 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Peaceful Co-existence-Detente Exchanging, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Helsinki Agreement, 1976-1986 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Madrid Conference, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Pronouncements-Western reactions-Interventions, 1962-1989 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - International Incidents, 1976-1985 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Contacts with International Organizations, 1978-1988 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - UN and UN Specialized Agencies, 1980-1987 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Amnesty International, 1977-1981 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Contacts with Émigré Circles Abroad-Citizens Abroad, 1978-1983 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Peace Activities, 1978-1988 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - World Assembly for Peace (Prague 1983), 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Visits General, 1977-1989 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Dissidents-Protests-Illegal Activities, 1976-1989 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - General References to Above Subjects (followed by year), 1968-1984 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Individuals, 1975-1999 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Individuals: Battek, Rudolf, 1980-1981 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Individuals: Fidelius, Peter, 1981-1984 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Individuals: Havel, Vaclav, 1966-1999 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Individuals: Havel, Vaclav (Writings), 1976-1989 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Individuals: Hutka, Jaroslav, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Individuals: Kyncl, Karel, 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Individuals: Lederer, Jiri, 1978-1983 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Individuals: Lis, Ladislav, 1980-1985 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Individuals: Palach, Jan, 1978-1984 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Individuals: Patocka, Jan, 1977-1987 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Individuals: Racek, Vaclav, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Individuals: Tesar, Jan, 1977-1980 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Individuals: Tomin, Julius, 1978-1995 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Protest-Discussions-Demonstrations, 1977-1989 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Czech Helsinki Committee, 1992-1996 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Charter 77 (Czech) (1 of 3), 1982-1989 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Charter 77 (Czech) (2 of 3), 1977-1985 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Charter 77 (Czech) (3 of 3), 1977-1985 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Charter 77 (English) (May 77) (1 of 2), 1977-1989 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Charter 77 (English) (May 77) (2 of 2), 1977-1985 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Charter 77 (1 of 2), 1977-1989 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Charter 77 (2 of 2), 1977-1987 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Charter 77 (English) (Jan. - Apr. 1977) (1 of 2), 1977-1989 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Charter 77 (English) (Jan. - Apr. 1977) (2 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Charter 77 (other languages), 1977-1987 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Charter 77 ( Russian ), 1977-1985 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Civil Liberty Movement, 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Imprisoned Dissidents-House Searches-Protests Against State Police, 1978-1989 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Charter 77 and Religion, 1977-1986 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Jokes-Cartoons, 1969-1988 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - VONS, 1977-1988 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Defections, 1963-1986 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Contacts with Foreigners, 1977-1989 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Samizdat Miscellany, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Publications, 1979-1985 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Samizdat Monographs, Anthologies, etc., 1980-1982 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Sbornik Milana Jankovicovi k padesatinam-Collection of M. Jankovic for the fiftieth birthday, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - International Peace Seminar (Prague 1988) (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Dissident Politics, Philosophy-Study groups, 1980-1998 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Dissident Cultural Activity, 1980-1988 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Dissident Youth Students, 1980-1989 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Czechoslovakian help to Ethiopia, 1985-1986 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Religion (1 of 2), 1967-2001 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Religion (2 of 2), 1967-2001 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Religion-General Interdenominational, 1961-1988, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Religion-History-1968, 1968-1987, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Religion-History (Samizdat writings), 1983-1989 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Ecumenical Movement, 1960-2001 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - World Council of Churches, 1978-1988 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Law and Religion, 1971-2002 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Conversions, 1977-1978 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Defection from Faith, 1977-1987 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Religion and Peace, 1965-1989 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Christian Peace Conference, 1968-1989 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Religion Abroad, 1977-1988 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Visits (Interdenominational), 1977-1987 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Official Religious Publications, 1976-1984 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Oppressive Practices Relating to Religious Activities, 1975-1980 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Defection-Emigration on Religious Grounds, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Relating to Religious Underground Activities, 1975-1989 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Religious Revival, 1966-1990 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Monasticism, 1974-1980 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Theology-Philosophy, etc., 1983-1989 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Religion and Science, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Religion and Official Pronouncements, 1976-1987 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Theological Education, 1977-1978, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Statistics, 1966-1986 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Religious Radio Broadcasts, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Religion and Culture, 1977-1998 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Bible, 1946-1989 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Religion-Art-Music-Culture, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Religion and Youth and Children, 1974-1988 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Sociology of Religion, 1969-1984 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Atheism, 1966-1984 (mostly 1970s) (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - History of atheism, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Individuals, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Atheists Propaganda (general), 1976, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Atheism in Education, Schools, Colleges, etc., 1976-1977 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Atheism in Youth and Children Organizations, 1975, 1982-1984 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Atheism in Press, 1974, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Atheist Books and Publications, 1976-1985 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Atheist Cults-Atheist Corners, etc., 1978 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Training in Atheist Work, Schools-Seminars on Atheism-Conferences, 1964, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Scientific Atheism-Philosophy of Atheism, 1972-1981 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Training in Atheist Work-Schools-Seminars on Atheism-Conferences, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Methods of Atheist Work, 1977-1978 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Criticism of Atheist Work, 1977-1984 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Atheism in Youth and Children Organizations, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Ideology-Philosophy-Communism-Morality, 1976-1988 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Communist Party of Czechoslovakia (C.P.C.), 1977-1987 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - History of C.P.C, 1976-1987 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Party Congresses-Party Decisions, 1976-1988 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Contacts with Other Communist and Related Parties, 1976-1988 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Mass Organizations-National Fronts, etc., 1977 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Purges-Ideological Deviations, 1976, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Individual Communists and Ideologists, 1976-1989 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Individual Communists and Ideologists: Dubcek, Alexander, 1970-1992 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Individual Communists and Ideologists: Husak, Gustav, 1971-1987 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Individual Communists and Ideologists: Svoboda, Ludvik, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Communism (General), 1966-1978 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Communism and Christianity, 1950-1977 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Ideology (General), 1963-1973 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Ideology (General), 1973-1978 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Proletarian Internationalism, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Ideological Propaganda Work-Education, 1975-1987 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Ideological Differences with Communist Countries and Parties, 1978, 1980-1981 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Ideological Differences with Communist Parties in the West, 1977-1978 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Ideological Differences with the West, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Ideological Propaganda from the West, 1973-1978 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Ideological and Religious Broadcasts from the West, 1980-1987 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Ideological Broadcast: Radio Liberty-Free Europe, 1976-1987 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Ideological Broadcast: Voice of America, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Ideological Broadcast: Transworld Radio, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Ideological Broadcast: Various Stations, 1984-1989 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Ideological Press and Publications in the West, 1975-1987 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Philosophy-Marxism/Marxism-Leninism, 1977-1984 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Ethics, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Morality, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Émigrés (living abroad), 1976-1979 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Ideology and Art-Ideology and Culture, 1977-1987 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Prague Spring, 1968-1989 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Soviet Invasion 1968 (1 of 4), 1968-1989 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Soviet Invasion 1968 (2 of 4), 1968-1989 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Soviet Invasion 1968 (3 of 4), 1968-1989 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Soviet Invasion 1968 (4 of 4), 1968-1989 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Agriculture, 1963-1987 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Economy, 1976-1989 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Labor, 1977-1978 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Education, 1969-1989 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Educational Institutions and Programs, 1977-1980 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Students, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Geography, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Ecology, 1984-1989 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Science, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Statistics, 1966-1982 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Health, Leisure, Sport, Tourism (General), 1988-1989 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Health, 1975-1987 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Psychology, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Tourism (1 of 2), 1964-1995 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Tourism (2 of 2), 1964-1996 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Holidays-Leisure, 1969, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Sport, 1977-2000 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Information Services-TV-Press-Radio, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - National Information Services (General), 1985-1987 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Television, 1987-1989 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Press, 1966-1987 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Journalists-Journalist Professional Bodies, 1977-1987 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Radio and Broadcasting, 1968-1987 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Culture, 1967-1987 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Theatre-Opera-Ballet, 1965-1987 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Cinema, 1977-1987 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Museums-Exhibitions, 1981-1989 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Cultural Trends, 1979-1981 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Literature, 1966-1984 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Individual Publications, 1980-1989 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Individual Writers, 1977-1998 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Individual Writers: Kohout, Pavel, 1978-1979 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Individual Writers: Kundera, Milan, 1977-1996 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Individual Writers: Seifert, Jaroslav, 1977-1986 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Individual Writers: Vaculik, Ludwik, 1967-1989 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Statistics, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Arts-Architecture-Music, 1983-1989 (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Music, 1972-2001 (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Art: Sculpture-Painting, 1962-1986 (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Unofficial Art, 1977-1987 (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Architecture Restoration, 1976-1989 (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Women, 1976-1987 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Children-Youth, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Youth, 1966-1984 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Party Youth Organization, 1977-1987 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Patterns of Youth Behavior (fashion, long hair), 1977-1988 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Youth Delinquency, 1977-1985 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Society-Family-Everyday Life, 1978-1987 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Social Problems, 1964-1989 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Family, 1965-1975 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Family Problems, 1973-1989 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Parental Rights, 1977-1988 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Everyday Life, 1967-1984 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Statistics, 1977-1989 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Social Services-Class Structure-Sociology, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Visual Material, 1964-1978 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - General References, 1962-1993, undated (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Rehabilitation of Jan Hus, 1986-1987, 1990, undated (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Jazz Dissident Case, 1987 February-March (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - International Relations. Soviet Union, 1987 March-April (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - BBC Reports, 1981-1991 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - KNS Reports, 1985-1991 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - United Bible Society Reports, 1985, 1990-1992 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - SWB Reports, 1983-1985, 1987, 1989 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - SWB Reports, 1990 (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - SWB Reports, 1991 (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - SWB Reports, 1992 (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - SWB Reports, 1993 (Box 35, Folder 15)
  - German Press Articles, 1975, 1978, 1981-1987, 1989 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - German Press Articles, 1990 March-April (Box 36, Folder 2)